MARCOS ANTÔNIO DE OLIVEIRA DERÓS

marcosderos78@gmail.com UFRGS, Instituto de Física

Av. Bento Gonçalves, 9500, 91509-900, Porto Alegre, RS, Brasil

SUMMARY

I was born in Porto Alegre, Brazil. I have been studying Physics since 2017, started to research on Particle Physics in 2019 through Geant4 simulations. My most recent my studies are the investigation of the performance of the ALPIDE chip for low energies and the validation of electron energy deposition for Geant4 versions from 9.6 to 11.0. Due to my research, I have experience with Project O^2 , Geant4 and data analysis with Python and ROOT.

EDUCATION

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

2017 - Present

Degree in Physics Final average: TBA

Undergraduate dissertation title: TBA

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

2021 - Present

Scientific Initiation Research

Advisor: Dr. Rafael Peretti Pezzi;

Project title: Studies on the ALPIDE Sensor Performance at Low Energies Regime and its Potential

for Ion Beam Analysis.

Grupo de Análise e Simulações de Partículas, Brazil

2021 - Present

Scientific Initiation Research Advisor: Dr. Gabriela Hoff;

Project title: Validation of Geant4 Simulation of Electron Energy Deposition.

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

2020 - Present

Scientific Initiation Research Fellowship

Advisor: Dr. Luis Gustavo Pereira;

Project title: Study on the Muon Dispersion in the ALICE's Absorber Using Geant4.

Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil

2019 - 2020

Scientific Initiation Research Fellowship

Advisor: Dr. Luis Gustavo Pereira;

Project title: Study on the Behavior of Cosmic Radiation in Earth's Atmosphere.

OUTREACH

Volunteer at the UFRGS Open Day

2018 and 2019

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Computer Languages C, C++, Python, Bash Software & Tools Geant4, ROOT, LaTeX

Languages Portuguese (native), Spanish (basic), English (advanced)